

### AMALIT = CH SERVICES

# **Al-Hussein**Frontend Developer

#### Skills/Proficiency\*

JavaScript (+++)
HTML (+++)
CSS (+++)
ReactJS/TS (++)
Tailwind CSS (++)
Bootstrap (++)
Typescript (+)
NextJS (+)

#### Tools

Git
GitHub
Vite
NPM
Yarn
Jira
Postman
VSCode

#### **Awards & Certifications**

Certificate of completion of Intro to Programming course in Udacity.

Certificate of completion of Codecademy Full stack Engineer course in Codecademy Jun 2021 to Sept 2021

Certificate of completion of Python for Everybody course in Coursera

\*Expert - Advanced - Intermediate - Basic ++++ +++ ++

#### **Work Experience**

AmaliTech Services GmbH, Takoradi, Ghana Associate (May 2023 to present) Junior Associate (Oct 2021 to Apr 2023)

- Collaborated with team to successfully develop high-quality front-end solution across four different projects, focusing on JavaScript and TypeScript based implementations using React.
- Review user requirements and create components, views, and advanced logic for various feature implementation.
- Use a varied of state management tools like redux and react query to manage state and data.

#### Selected Project Experience

Incident Management System:

- Contributed to the development of an intuitive and user-friendly interface of an incident management system using React and JavaScript
- Review user requirements and create components, views, and advanced logic for various feature implementation.
- Test major features, as well as work collaboratively with other team members to deliver complex change within deadlines.

#### AmaliTech Event Management Platform:

- Led a team to develop an event management dashboard web application for admin and event organizers to populate data and events to mobile app using react, typescript and tailwindess.
- Successfully implemented state management using tanstack react query tools.
- Implemented authentication and authorization functionality using JWT to secure end point and control access.



#### Languages\*

English (+++) Twi (+++)

#### The Fairwork Platform:

- Collaborate with team to reduce code smell by 35% and bug by 80%.
- Collaborate with other team members to implement Thefairwork platform blog using NextJS.
- Developed features for platform for African tech talent, working with React and JavaScript.
- Ensured the adaptability of all pages, overseeing their responsiveness.
- Transformed app designs into frontend code with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Installed, configured, and maintained network services equipment and device.

#### MarketPlace:

- Worked on a community platform marketplace using react to connect local and small-scale business to potential customers.
- Transformed app designs into frontend code with React, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Implemented delivery tracking functionality.
- Implemented responsive designs on all pages to accurately adapt to all devices.

#### Education

#### **Graduate Training Programme**

Institution: AmaliTech gGmbH, Takoradi, Ghana *Year of Graduation: 2021* 

 Specialization: Software Engineering (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, PostgreSQL)

## Bachelor of Arts Social Sciences (Geography and Sociology)

Institution: University of Cape Coast, Cape Coast, Ghana *Year of Graduation: 2017*